sodahead.com 2015-06-29

# SodaHead.com - Privacy

Date Last Modified: May , 2012. 

SodaHead, Inc. ("SodaHead") recognizes that its visitors, members, users, and others who use the Website at www.SodaHead.com (the "SodaHead Website"), (collectively or individually you, your, "Users") value their privacy. This Privacy Notice provides important information about the use and disclosure of User information collected on the SodaHead Website. SodaHead provides this Privacy Notice to help you understand what information SodaHead collects and how that information will be used. 

This Privacy Notice is incorporated into and is subject to the SodaHead Terms of Use. Your use of the SodaHead Website and any personal information you provide on the SodaHead Website remains subject to the terms of this Privacy Notice and our Terms of Use. 

By participating, using or viewing the SodaHead Website or any content thereof you are accepting the practices described in our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to any of these terms, then please do not use the SodaHead Website or its Content. We reserve the right to modify or amend the terms of our Privacy Policy at any time without prior notice. Your continued use of the SodaHead Website following the posting of changes to these terms means that you accept those changes. 

If you have any questions or comments about the SodaHead privacy policy, please contact us. 

The Information Collected by SodaHead

_Information Provided by You_ : You provide personally identifiable information (such as your name and email address) to SodaHead when you become a member of the SodaHead community and other information by choosing to participate in various activities on the SodaHead Website such as creating polls posting comments or messages, participating in discussions, etc. 

_Cookies_ : Use of "Cookies" is standard in the Internet industry. Cookies are small text files containing a string of alphanumeric characters that are sent to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. Cookies make web surfing easier by saving passwords, and preferences while you're at a website. When you visit the SodaHead Website, we may send one or more cookies to your computer. Some cookies are temporary and will disappear after you close your browser, but others will stay on your computer. If you wish to remove cookies from your hard drive, follow your web browser help file directions. You can also reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the SodaHead Website may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled. 

_Traffic Data_ : When you use the SodaHead Website, our servers automatically log certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit any website. This information may include information such as your web your Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, browser language, referring/exit pages and URLs, platform type, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed and the order of those pages, the amount of time spent on particular pages, the date and time of your request, and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser. 

_Tracking Usage Patterns_ : SodaHead tracks usage patterns and collects other non-personally-identifiable information about use of the SodaHead Website. We may employ various tracking technology including "clear GIFs" (a.k.a. Web Beacons) which are used to track the online usage patterns of our Users (in a way that does not collect or disclose personally-identifiable information), and clear GIFs in HTML-based emails sent to you to track which emails are opened by recipients. 

The Way SodaHead Uses Information

Personally identifiable information that you submit to us through the SodaHead Website, will be used by SodaHead to provide to you the features and functionality of the SodaHead Website and to operate and maintain the SodaHead Website. 

Any personal information, text or other content that you voluntarily provide in the course of your use of the SodaHead website, including but not limited to, information in your Member Profile, by participating in polls, discussions, comments and communities, is publicly available. Your User Name (but not your email address) is displayed to other Users in connection with the polls you create and messages you post in discussions. Any information that you post on the SodaHead Website may be redistributed by SodaHead and viewed by the general public. 

We will not sell or otherwise distribute your personally identifiable information to third parties. However, SodaHead may use your email address or other personally identifiable information to send commercial and marketing messages, and market research related surveys and other offers to you. You have an opportunity to opt-in or opt-out of any such programs by selecting the Change My Settings link, under Controls on the My Dashboard page, or by sending an e-mail to [privacy@SodaHead.com](mailto:privacy@SodaHead.com) with the term "BLOCK" (in all caps) in the subject line. We will also use your email address for non-marketing or administrative purposes (such as notifying you of major SodaHead Website changes or for customer service purposes). 

We will also use both your personally identifiable information and certain non-personally-identifiable information (such as usage data, server log information, cookies, IP addresses, browser type, other technical data, etc.) to improve the quality and design of the SodaHead Website and to create new features, functionality, and services by storing, tracking, and analyzing User preferences and trends. 

We use cookies, clear gifs, and log file information to: (a) to assist with your use of the Website by "remembering" information so that you will not have to re-enter it during subsequent visits to the SodaHead Website; (b) provide customized, personalized content and information for you; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, pages viewed, etc.; and (e) track your entries, submissions, and status in promotions, sweepstakes, and contests. 

When SodaHead Discloses Information

We will not share your personally identifiable information (such as name or email address) with other, third-party companies for their commercial or marketing use without your consent or except as part of a specific program or feature for which you will have the ability to opt-in or opt-out. 

We may share non-personally-identifiable information (such as traffic information and usage tracking information) with interested third-parties to assist them in understanding the usage patterns for certain content, services, advertisements, promotions, and/or functionality on the SodaHead Website. 

We may provide personally identifiable information and non-personally-identifiable information to our subsidiaries, affiliated companies, or other businesses or persons in connection with the limited purpose of outsourcing of technical functions. We require that these parties agree to process such information in compliance with our privacy policy, and we use reasonable efforts to limit their use of such information and to use other appropriate confidentiality and security measures. 

We reserve the right to release personally identifiable information and/or non-personally-identifiable information if required to do so by law, or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with state and federal laws (such as U.S. Copyright Law) or respond to a court order, subpoena, or search warrant. 

SodaHead also reserves the right to disclose personally identifiable information and/or non-personally-identifiable information that SodaHead believes, in good faith, is appropriate or necessary to enforce our Terms of Use, take precautions to avoid liability, to investigate and defend itself against any third-party claims or allegations, to assist government enforcement agencies, to protect the security or integrity of our website, and to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of SodaHead, our Users or others. 

Your Options

You may decline to submit personally identifiable information through the SodaHead Website, but if you do certain aspects of the SodaHead experience will not be available to you. You may update or correct your personal profile information and email preferences at any time by visiting the Controls section on the My Dashboard page. 

To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you access, or making corrections, to your profile. It is your responsible to maintain the secrecy of your unique password and account information at all times. 

Third-party Advertisers, Links to Other Sites

SodaHead allows other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to serve advertisements within the SodaHead Website. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear on the SodaHead Websites. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies or other tracking technologies) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize the advertising content you see. 

SodaHead does not provide any personally identifiable information to these third-party ad servers or ad networks without your consent or except as part of a specific program or feature for which you will have the ability to opt-in or opt-out. However, please note that if you respond to any advertisements, the advertiser or ad-server may collect certain information about you. 

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers or ad networks (see links below) for more information on their practices and for instructions on how to opt-out of certain practices. SodaHead's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or websites. 

(1) State that the site’s advertisers may engage in the collection of non-personally identifiable information about end users by third parties through the use of cookies and pixel tags;     (2) Enable end users to opt out of behavioral targeting through the opt-out link located at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>; and     (3) Note that you are participating in the Digital Advertising Alliance's (DAA) Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising, with the provision an "Ad Choices" link on your site or within advertising units that links to <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>. 

Data Security

SodaHead uses commercially reasonable safeguards (physical, managerial, and technical) to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information. However, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to SodaHead and you transmit any such information at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, SodaHead makes commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. 

If SodaHead learns of a security systems breach, then we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. 

Childrens' Privacy

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, SodaHead does not knowingly collect or maintain personally identifiable information or non-personally-identifiable information on the SodaHead Website from persons under 13 years of age, and no part of our website is directed to persons under 13. If you are under 13 years of age, then please do not use or access the SodaHead Website at any time or in any manner. If SodaHead learns that personally identifiable information of persons under 13 years of age has been collected on the SodaHead Website without verified parental consent, then SodaHead will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. 

International Users

The SodaHead Website are hosted in the United States and are intended for and directed to Users in the United States. If you are a User accessing the SodaHead Website from the European Union, Asia, or any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure, that differ from United States laws, please be advised that through your continued use of the SodaHead Website, which are governed by U.S. law, this Privacy Notice, and our Terms of Use, you are transferring your personal information to the United States and you consent to that transfer. 

Changes to this Privacy Notice

This Privacy Notice may be revised from time to time and this will be reflected by the "effective date" above. Please revisit this page to stay aware of any changes. In general, we only use your personal information in the manner described in the Privacy Notice in effect when we received the personal information you provided. Your continued use of the SodaHead Website constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Notice and any future revisions.
